trademotion.com 2015-06-07

# Privacy Policy - TradeMotion.com

You are here: [Home](http://cdn.trademotion.com/ "TradeMotion.com") / Privacy Policy

### Effective Date: 02/13/2015

Your privacy is important to TradeMotion, Inc. (“TradeMotion”); maintaining your trust is paramount to us. This Statement details the information practices for TradeMotion’s (www.trademotion.com) and our affiliates’ Web sites, including what type of information is gathered and tracked, how the information is used, and with whom the information is shared.

This Statement applies to TradeMotion Web sites that link to this Statement but does not apply to TradeMotion or TradeMotion-affiliated Websites that have their own Privacy Statement. Additionally, it does not apply to instances where we merely process data on behalf of clients for their benefit, such as when we act as a web hosting service provider. From time to time, we may supplement this Statement with additional information relating to a particular interaction we have with you.

  * Collection of Personal Information
  * Use of Personal Information
  * Sharing of Personal Information and International Transfers
  * Information Security and Accuracy
  * Cookies, Web Beacons and Other Technologies
  * Online Advertising
  * Links to Non-TradeMotion Web Sites and Third Party Applications
  * Notification of Changes
  * Privacy Questions and Access

You may choose to give us personal information directly in a variety of circumstances. For example, you may want to give us your name and contact information to communicate with you, to process an order, to provide you with a subscription or a service, or to do business with us if you are a supplier or a business partner. If you tell us that you do not want us to use your information to make further contact with you beyond fulfilling your request, we will respect your request.

We may also collect information relating to your use of our Web sites through the use of various technologies. For example, when you visit our Web sites, we may log certain information that your browser sends us, such as your IP address, browser type and language, access time, and referring Web site addresses. We may also collect information about the pages you view within our sites and other actions you take while visiting us. In addition, we may also use such technologies to determine whether you’ve opened an e-mail or clicked on a link contained in an e-mail. Collecting information in this manner allows us to collect statistics about our Web sites usage and effectiveness and personalize your experience while you are on our Web sites, as well as tailor our interactions with you. For details regarding the technologies we employ, see “Cookies, Web Beacon and Other Technologies” below.

From time to time, we may also collect information that pertains to you indirectly through other sources, such as list vendors. When we do so, we ask the vendors to confirm that the information was legally acquired by the third party, and that we have the right to obtain it from them and use it.

The information that we collect, either directly or indirectly, may be combined to help us improve its overall accuracy and completeness and to help us better tailor our interactions with you.

The information that we collect, either directly or indirectly, may be combined to help us improve its overall accuracy and completeness and to help us better tailor our interactions with you.

The following paragraphs describe in more detail how TradeMotion may use your personal information.

###  Fulfilling your Transaction Request

If you request something from TradeMotion, for example, a product or service, a callback, or specific marketing materials, we will use the information you provide to fulfill your request. To help us do this, we may share information with others, for instance, TradeMotion’s business partners, financial institutions, shipping companies, or postal or government authorities, such as Customs authorities, involved in fulfillment. In connection with a transaction, we may also contact you as part of our customer satisfaction surveys or for market research purposes.

### Personalizing your Experience on our Web Sites

We may use information we collect about you to provide you with a personalized experience on our Web sites, such as providing you with content in which you may be interested and making navigation on our sites easier.

### Providing Support

We may use your personal information to support products or services you have obtained from us, such as notifying you of a product update or fix.

We also provide “Live Chat” sessions on our Web sites to assist you while you’re navigating through our sites; we will use personal information you provide via these sessions in accordance with this Privacy Statement.

In the course of providing technical support to you, we may sometimes have incidental access to data that you have provided to us or data that is located on your system. This data may contain information about you, your organization’s employees, customers, partners, or suppliers. This Privacy Statement does not apply to our access to or handling of this information; the conditions regarding the handling and processing of that data is covered by the applicable Terms of Use or other agreements between you and TradeMotion, such as the Terms of Use for Exchanging Diagnostic Data.

### Marketing

The information you provide to TradeMotion, as well as the information we have collected about you indirectly, may be used by TradeMotion for marketing purposes. Before we do so, however, we will offer you the opportunity to choose whether or not to have your information used in this way. You may at any time choose not to receive marketing materials from us by following the unsubscribe instructions included in each e-mail you may receive, by indicating so when we call you, or by contacting us directly (please refer to “Privacy Questions and Access” below).

Some of our offerings may be co-branded, that is sponsored by both TradeMotion and third parties. If you sign up for these offerings, be aware that your information may also be collected by and shared with those third parties. We encourage you to familiarize yourself with their privacy policies to gain an understanding of the manner in which they will handle information about you.

### Monitoring or Recording of Calls, Chats and Other Interactions

Certain online transactions may involve you calling us or us calling you. They may also involve online chats. Please be aware that it is TradeMotion’s general practice to monitor and in some cases record such interactions for staff training or quality assurance purposes or to retain evidence of a particular transaction or interaction.

### Protect the Rights and Property of TradeMotion and Others

We may also use or share your information to protect the rights or property of TradeMotion, our business partners, suppliers, clients, or others when we have reasonable grounds to believe that such rights or property have been or could be affected. In addition, we reserve the right to disclose your personal information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, or the rights of others, or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Web sites.

### Information for Business Partners

If you represent a TradeMotion business partner, you may visit TradeMotion Web sites intended specifically for TradeMotion business partners. We may use information provided on that site to administer and develop our business relationship with you, the business partner you represent, and TradeMotion business partners generally. For instance, this may involve using your information to send you details of TradeMotion business partner programs. It may also include sharing certain information with other business partners (subject to any confidentiality obligations that may exist), or TradeMotion customers or prospects. In connection with a particular transaction or program, we may also contact you as part of customer satisfaction surveys or for market research purposes.

### Information for Suppliers

If you represent a TradeMotion supplier, you may visit TradeMotion Web sites intended specifically for use by TradeMotion suppliers. We may use the information provided on that site in connection with entering into or performing a transaction with you. For example, this may include sharing information with other parts of TradeMotion, TradeMotion’s business partners, customers, shipping companies, financial institutions and postal or government authorities involved in fulfillment. It may also be used to administer and develop our relationship with you, the supplier you represent, and other TradeMotion suppliers generally.

TradeMotion is a global organization with business processes, management structures and technical systems that cross borders. As such, we may share information about you within TradeMotion and transfer it to countries in the world where we do business in connection with the uses identified above and in accordance with this Privacy Statement. Our Privacy Statement and our practices are designed to provide a globally consistent level of protection for personal information all over the world. This means that even in countries whose laws provide for less protection for your information, TradeMotion will still handle your information in the manner described here.

In some cases, TradeMotion uses suppliers located in various countries to collect, use, analyze, and otherwise process information on its behalf. It is TradeMotion’s practice to require such suppliers to handle information in a manner consistent with TradeMotion’s policies.

From time to time, we may disclose information that identifies you at an individual level and which we collected on our Web sites to other non-TradeMotion entities that are not acting as our suppliers, such as our business partners. Except as described in this Privacy Statement, we will only do so with your prior consent. We do not sell or lease such information however.

Circumstances may arise where, whether for strategic or other business reasons, TradeMotion decides to sell, buy, merge or otherwise reorganize businesses in some countries. Such a transaction may involve the disclosure of personal information to prospective or actual purchasers, or the receipt of such information from sellers. It is TradeMotion’s practice to seek appropriate protection for information in these types of transactions.

Please be aware that in certain circumstances, personal information may be subject to disclosure to government agencies pursuant to judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process. We may also share your information to protect the rights or property of TradeMotion, our business partners, suppliers or clients, and others when we have reasonable grounds to believe that such rights or property have been or could be affected.

We intend to protect your personal information and to maintain its accuracy. TradeMotion implements reasonable physical, administrative and technical safeguards to help us protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use and disclosure. For example, we encrypt certain sensitive personal information such as credit card information when we transmit such information over the Internet. We also require that our suppliers protect such information from unauthorized access, use and disclosure. If you have any questions regarding security please contact us at [info@TradeMotion.com](mailto:info@trademotion.com). 

### Retention

We will retain your registration information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to request that we no longer use your registration information to provide you services or if you would like to request the updating or deletion of your personal information, contact us at [info@TradeMotion.com](mailto:info@trademotion.com). We will retain and use your registration information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

As mentioned above, we collect information from your visits to our Web sites to help us gather statistics about our Web sites usage and effectiveness, personalize your experience on our sites, and tailor our interactions with you.

We do so through the use of various technologies, including one called “cookies”. A cookie is a piece of data that a Web site can send to your browser, which may then be stored on your computer as a tag that identifies your computer. While cookies are often only used to measure Web site usage and effectiveness and to allow for ease of navigation or use and as such, are not associated with any personal information, they are also used at times to personalize a known visitor’s experience to a Web site by being associated with profile information or user preferences. You can set your browser in most instances to notify you before you receive a cookie, giving you the chance to decide whether to accept it or not. You can also generally set your browser to turn off cookies. Since cookies allow you to take advantage of some of our Web sites’ features, we recommend that you leave them turned on. If you block or otherwise reject our cookies, you will not be able, for instance, to add items to your shopping cart, proceed to checkout, or use any Web site services that require you to sign in.

Some TradeMotion Web sites also use Web beacon or other technologies to better tailor those sites to provide better customer service. These technologies may be in use on a number of pages across TradeMotion’s Web sites. When a visitor accesses these pages, a non-identifiable notice of that visit is generated which may be processed by us or by our suppliers. These Web beacons usually work in conjunction with cookies. If you don’t want your cookie information to be associated with your visits to these pages, you can set your browser to turn off cookies. If you turn off cookies, Web beacon and other technologies will still detect visits to these pages; however, they will not be associated with information otherwise stored in cookies.

We may also include Web beacons in marketing e-mail messages or our newsletters in order to determine whether messages have been opened and links contained within clicked on.

Some of our business partners set Web beacons and cookies on our site. In addition third-party social media buttons may log certain information such as your IP address, browser type and language, access time, and referring Web site addresses, and, if you are logged in to those social media sites, they may also link such collected information with your profile information on that site. We do not control these third party tracking technologies.

TradeMotion does not deliver third party online advertisements on our Web sites but we advertise our products and services on others’ Web sites. We may collaborate with Web site operators as well as network advertisers to do so. Please familiarize yourself with those Web site operators’ or network advertisers’ privacy policies to understand their practices relating to advertising, including what type of information they may collect about your Internet usage. TradeMotion does not provide any information relating to your usage of TradeMotion Web sites to Web site operators or network advertisers. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by [clicking here](http://preferences.truste.com/). Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising.  You will continue to receive generic ads.

To allow you to interact with other Web sites on which you may have accounts (such as Facebook and other social media sites) or join communities on such sites, we may provide links or embed third-party applications that allow you to login, post content or join communities from our Web sites.

These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. In addition, they are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our site. 

We may also provide you with general links to non-TradeMotion Web sites.

Your use of these links and applications is subject to the third parties’ privacy policies, and you should become familiar with the third party sites’ privacy policies before using the links or applications.

TradeMotion is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of those other Web sites.

We will post a notice for 30 days at the top of this page notifying users when this Privacy Statement is updated or modified in a material way. If we are going to use your personal information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection, we will notify you, and you will have a choice as to whether or not we can use your personal information in such a way.

If you have a question about this Privacy Statement or TradeMotion’s handling of your information, you can send an email to the TradeMotion Web site coordinator at [info@TradeMotion.com](mailto:info@trademotion.com). You can also contact us at:

**TradeMotion’s Corporate Privacy Office:**  
2190 Carmel Valley Rd. Suite D  
Del Mar, CA 92014

In certain cases, you may have the ability to view or edit your personal information online. In the event your information is not accessible online, and you wish to obtain a copy of particular information you provided to TradeMotion, or if you become aware the information is incorrect and you would like us to correct it, Contact Us.

Before TradeMotion is able to provide you with any information or correct any inaccuracies, however, we may ask you to verify your identity and to provide other details to help us to respond to your request. We will contact you within 30 days of your request.

If you have questions or concerns regarding our Privacy Statement, please contact TradeMotion via the means provided on our website.  
If you no longer wish to receive marketing e-mails from TradeMotion, please send an e-mail to [info@TradeMotion.com](mailto:info@trademotion.com) or follow the unsubscribe instructions included in each marketing email.

### Scope

The TradeMotion Online Privacy Statement applies to TradeMotion’s and our affiliates’ Web sites that link to the Statement. Below are some of the highlights of the Statement.

### Personal Information

  * We collect your personal information for various purposes, such as processing your order, corresponding with you, providing you with a subscription or in connection with a job application.
  * We collect your personal information for various purposes, such as processing your order, corresponding with you, providing you with a subscription or in connection with a job application.
  * In addition, we may also collect information relating to your use of our Web sites through the use of various technologies, including cookies.

### Uses

  * To fulfill your requests by us or by others involved in fulfillment.
  * To contact you for customer satisfaction surveys, market research or in connection with certain transactions.
  * To support products or services you have obtained from us.
  * By TradeMotion and selected organizations for marketing purposes if you have permitted such use.
  * To personalize your experience while you are on our sites, make navigation easier, and for Web site usage statistics.

### Your Choices

When we collect information from you, you may tell us that you do not want it used for further marketing contact.  
You may also turn off cookies in your browser.

### Important Information

If you have any complaints regarding our compliance with our privacy policy or statement, you should first [Contact Us.](http://cdn.trademotion.com/contact/)

To find out more about our privacy practices, see the [TradeMotion Online Privacy Statement](http://cdn.trademotion.com/privacy-policy/).

Questions about this statement or about TradeMotion’s handling of your information may be sent to:

TradeMotion Inc.  
2190 Carmel Valley Rd. Suite D  
Del Mar, CA 92014

If you do not want to receive future marketing communications from TradeMotion, including subscriptions, please send an email to [info@TradeMotion.com](mailto:info@trademotion.com).
